8 St Judes Road Wolverhampton Wv6 0EB 07969269851 JAMIE@JEDESIGN.XYZ HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JAMIEMUFU

JAMIE EVANS

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Highly motivated and determined self-taught web developer. Has a drive to learn the best programming practices to build web applications with the latest web technologies. Possesses excellent written and verbal communication skills. Works extremely well in a team and on his own and works well under pressure. Looking for a new career in web development. I have the skills, personality and passion to succeed. Took on as Trainee front end developer and worked my way up to Middleweight Full Stack developer.

EDUCATION

MILFORD HAVEN COMPREHENSIVE - Milford Haven, Wales

GCSE: Maths(C), English(C), Science Double(CC),, Information Technology
Double(AA), Technical Design(B), French (D), Religious Education(C), Welsh(D),
Geography(D).

A Levels: Computer Science double and Information Technology

FreeCodeCamp.org: An online resource for learning HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Includes a course map and certificates.

Udemy: Colt Steele Web Dev Bootcamp / Advanced CSS/Flexbox. Flutter Master Course, Master PHP Class (custom CMS).

Linkedin Learning: Linux Foundation, PHPCourses, https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamie-evans-2aba1515a/

PORTFOLIO

JEDESIGN.XYZ - Portfolio website.

Built on Laravel with a custom CMS for adding projects easily, hosted myself via AWS and EC2. Code is available on my Github.

- Projects here can be viewed and links to github provided
- Used SCSS/SASS. Bootstrap, JQuery, PHP and JS.
- Have done work for some big companies such as Weight Waters, Namco funscape and Grosvenor Casinos.

TECHNOLOGIES AND SKILLS

COMFORTABLE - Languages and frameworks I work confidently in.

Languages: HTML5, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Dart.

Frameworks/Libraries: : Vue.js, Laravel, Flutter, Craft3 CMS, Bootstrap, Sass, Material UI, Whsky, Symfony, JQuery, WordPress, Symfony.

Tools: Ansible, Semaphore CI, Git, Github, Chrome Dev Tools, Dart Dev Tools, RESTful APIs, AJAX, JSON, SSH, Webkit, NPM, Bower, GULP.

Dev-ops: Linux server administration, creating new projects and dev sites, Continuous Integration from Semaphore, Ansible for settings up new projects, Managing SSL installation and CRON management, SSH and SSH management (adding and removing keys), Github and deployments, Command line and shell scripts.

FUTURE AND INTERESTS - Languages and frameworks I want to learn and interested in using at some point.

Languages: Python, JS, Swift, C#

Frameworks/Libraries: : Node.js, more competence with Flutter. Flutter is soon coming to web and desktop, I have dabbled in App Development with it and seems a joy to work with.

Tools: Docker

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS AND SKILLS

- Ability to adapt extremely well to different environments and work tasks.
- Ability to learn, develop and focus on anything that's thrown my way.
- Proven record of going above and beyond what is asked and always give my best.
- Confidence in my own abilities and not afraid to ask for help.
- I genuinely enjoy problem solving and thinking of different ways to solve problems.
- Within 6 months, I got promoted from Trainee HTML email developer to Full Stack Developer after proving my ability to learn.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SUPERCOOL DESIGN - Back end Developer

Jan 2020 - Current, Fully Remote - Currently Furloughed

This is a fully remote position, with flexible working hours. Supercool Design makes websites for large theatre companies and supplies them with a full site with booking and payments via Spektrix. They also use Craft3 and Vue.JS. PHP being the back end language, with Vue.js being the front end framework they use.

As a backend developer my day to day tasks were fixing bugs and devops tasks. Such as setting up new projects, maintaining SSL certs and CronJobs, configuring and running Semaphore Continuous Integration. Also there are many API's that need to be integrated and configured into any new project. Some of these are Spektrix, Algolia, Google maps, Spektrix to name a few. I had first hand experience working with some of these complex API's and fixing major bugs.

I got more involved with Linux Server Administration, creating and amending server configurations (Apache2, NGINX), creating imports via CronJobs and Slack alerts via StatusCake.

I recently had the fairly big task of exporting a WordPress site's data and importing it into Craft3 CMS. This was quite challenging and involved exporting the site data as XML and then re-writing the XML programmatically so Craft3 could read the data and import the data properly. It was a success and saved weeks of manually copy/pasting over sections and category posts from the WordPress site. This was done via PHP and custom build Craft CMS plugin.

INSPIRED THINKING GROUP - Junior Front-end Dev (promoted to full stack)

Feb 2018 - Jan 2020, Fort Dunlop, Birmingham

This was my first role in the industry, initially taken on as a trainee front-end developer to work on the marketing emails, and working my way within 6 months to Full Stack Developer. After my initial 3 months probation period I was immediately recognised as having more skills and experience than initially thought and was offered a 20% pay rise and an internal promotion from Trainee front-end to junior back-end then to full-stack a few months after that.

My skills and passion were immediately recognised and after getting involved in projects outside of my current skills set was recognised to be capable of more than just front-end.

- I swiftly moved on to doing some basic JavaScript validation for forms and then leading onto landing pages built entirely myself using php/vanilla JS and LESS/SASS, capturing basic user information into databases.
- Due to becoming junior back-end I started learning the basics of linux and gaining experience of git and different workflows, evolving into using webpack, gulp, npm many things initially foreign to me from the initial job I applied for.

HOYER - ESSO/SHELL CONTRACT - Fuel Tanker Driver

Nov 2016 - Feb 2018, Tamworth

I relocated to the midlands for this job. Extremely good pay rise and working hours. Very similar to my previous job with Turners but with more pay and better working conditions. Scope for promotion was low. I ultimately left this job (on good terms) to focus entirely on web development. I lost interest in driving commercially over the years. Around the time I decided to code in my spare time coincidentally.

- Much more team focused with senior drivers and team-leaders.
- Very paperwork oriented. General math used frequently to work out space available at forecourts.

TURNERS OF SOHAM - Fuel Tanker Driver

Sep 2013 - Nov 2016, Cardiff

My first driving job and civilian full time job leaving the Army. Gained some very useful skills and experience. Reporting to the office and problems which arose during delivery or loading of dangerous goods. A Lot of responsibility as mainly working on your own. After a year I got promoted to regional driver trainer due to my ability to work well with others and my calm but effective approach to problems and solving problems.

- Gained experience working shifts and nights.
- Promoted in the first year to a regional position.
- Worked using skills and qualifications I gained from the Army.

BRITISH ARMY - Welsh Guards (Infantry)

Sep 2009 - 2013, London

This was my first "career" leaving school. The training was arduous, long, physical and emotionally draining. Tip of the spear, front-line role. I thought if I was going to do it, I would do it properly. Experienced everything the Army has to offer. During my time here I gained invaluable skills. Progressed through the ranks and did course after course after course. Eventually trained to be a sniper. I learned a lot about myself, what I could do and how much grit and determination I really had.

- Gained all my driving licenses and my carriage of dangerous goods
- Was part of trooping of the color twice.
- Served overseas.
- Gained life-experience.

ABOUT

Originally from Wales, I moved to Midlands to be with my partner and there were better job opportunities for entry level developers. I worked hard, by any means I could get, to teach myself the fundamentals of web development. In my spare time I enjoy playing video games (Esports - It's a thing now apparently) and going to gigs and seeing my favorite bands all over. I used to also skateboard and compete in my younger days. Unfortunately I have outgrown that now. But I try to stay involved with that community as best as I can.